<Document>
  # Space Law
  Nanotrasen stations operate under space law. All crew, passengers, and visitors aboard the station are subject to space law.

  Foreign invaders, such as nuclear operatives, ninjas, and pirates, are not protected under space law.

  ## Treatment Of Prisoners
  Prisoners still have certain rights that must be upheld by law enforcement:
  - Prisoners must be granted adequate medical care.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to basic communications equipment (Radios) so long as they are not abused.
  - Prisoners must be granted clothing, food, water, shelter and safety. If the brig is no longer safe, confinement must be established in another location.
  - Prisoners must be given access to legal counsel during an interrogation if requested and available.
  - Prisoners must be granted freedom of movement within the brig, and should not be restrained with handcuffs or other devices after incarceration unless they present an undue risk to life and limb.

  ## Search and Seizure
  A personnel search is a seizure of objects in a person's possession. Searches are conducted to check whether someone is in possession of contraband, or to obtain evidence surrounding a crime. All items which are not contraband or connected to a crime must be returned.

  A crewmate may decline any search conducted without probable cause or a warrant while the alert level is green. If the alert level is blue or above, all personnel searches are legal.

  A departmental search is the sweep of an entire area or department for contraband. These can only be done with a warrant signed by the respective department head or highest-ranking command staff.

  ## Implantation
  Any prisoner in custody can be subjected to implanting/extracting procedures, so long as it's within reason.

  The process of adding or extracting an implant should not prolong the detainees sentence, meaning you can not hold them longer to perform the procedure.

  ## Foreign Invaders
  Hostile foreign invaders should be put into confinement when possible. If security is unable to effectively keep them detained, execution is recommended.

  ## Sentencing
  [color=#a4885c]Stackable Crimes:[/color] Crimes are to be considered 'stackable' in the sense that if you charge someone with two or more crimes, you should combine the times you would give them for each crime.
  Linked crimes, shown in matching colors and suffixes on the Quick Crime Guide, can not be stacked and instead override each other, you should pick the highest crime that matches the case.

  - Example: A suspect has committed a 2-01 (possession: major) and a 3-01 (possession: highly illegal). The maximum sentence here would be 10 minutes due to them being linked crimes, and 3-01 is the greater crime.
  - Example 2: A suspect commits a 3-04 (Secure trespassing) and a 3-06 (manslaughter). Those crimes stack since they are not linked crimes. You could sentence for a maximum of 20 minutes, but context matters heavily, and maximum sentences should only be used for the worst offenders.

  [color=#a4885c]Repeat Offenders:[/color] Repeated crimes are when someone is released for a crime and then goes to commit the same crime within the same shift.
  Repeated crimes can be charged with tacked-on time.
  - first repeat: 3:00
  - second repeat: 6:00
  - third repeat: permanent confinement.

  [color=#a4885c]Accessory, Attempting, And Intention:[/color] If someone intentionally, knowingly, and substantially assists someone in enacting a crime, they can be charged with the relevant crime. The same applies for attempting a crime, even if it wasn't fully carried out.

  ## Major Punishments
  <!-- Moffstation - perma timing changes -->
  [color=#a4885c]Permanent Confinement:[/color] Being held in the permanent brig for the entire duration of the shift. A person is eligible for permanent confinement if they have committed a capital crime. Any persons subject to this punishment are required to be transported in cuffs to CentComm at the end of the shift. A permanent prisoner can not be deprived of anything covered by the section "Treatment Of Prisoners".
  <!-- Moffstation- update execution requirements -->
  [color=#a4885c]Execution and DNRs:[/color] A humane way of dealing with extremely unruly crewmates. Prisoners who have committed a capital crime, or have proven via their actions that they are unable to be safely kept in confinement are eligible for execution with the approval of the Captain. If there is no available captain, a majority command vote can used for approval instead.

  Within reason, a prisoner who has been given the death sentence may pick how they wish to be killed, common methods are firing line, lethal injection, exile, and high voltage electrocution. Another alternate method of "execution" is the process of placing a staff's mind into a borg, this is allowed so long as it is lawful. Additionally, a Do-Not-Revive order can be placed on criminals who are deemed to be worthy of execution but are killed before being detained.

  ## Crime Listing
  - [textlink="Crime Listing" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"]
</Document>
