<Document>
  # Section 3: Powergaming

  3.1 Do not powergame. That is, minmaxing to try and achieve the best possible results to the point of being detrimental to roleplay, rushing to acquire strong or useful equipment you do not need, performing meta tricks and exploits that are unfair or unfit for a roleplay environment, and so forth.

  3.2 Greytiding (ignoring ones job duties to instead gather materials, "loot", and generally be delinquent or perform petty crime) as a non-antagonist is allowed so long as it is not to an excessive degree. This is largely dependent on the role you are playing in the round. Generally, jobs with higher esteem, responsibilities, and obligations are expected to greytide much less than others.
  - It is unreasonable for members of command to greytide, but they may request a member of their department to do so.

  3.3  Do not rush for, hoard, or prepare equipment unrelated to your job or that you do not need. If you, in your given role, require items that do not fall within your job’s usual parameters or that you do not necessarily need, seek in-character roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them.
  - Permits stamped by the head of your department, the Head of Personnel, or the Captain are roleplay-friendly methods.

  3.4 As a non-antagonist, manufacturing dangerous, powerful or/and out-of-the-norm items such as weapons, bombs, deadly poisons, specialized machinery, or obstructive structures without reasonable emergency or need, is liable to be considered powergaming behavior. Seek in-character, roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them outside of emergency or strict need.

  3.5 As a non-antagonist, don't intentionally hide antagonist objectives in unreasonable locations. If you are an antagonist, refrain from stealing these items unless you actually intend on using them, or have one as your objective.
  - For example, handing a possible antagonist objective to another member of your department is fine, while handing it to a member of a different department is not.
  - It is reasonable to assume that an item such as the handheld crew monitor or hypospray may be in the possession of another member of the medical staff, but not an engineer.
  - Hiding a possible antagonist objective somewhere in your room is okay, hiding it in a room where it cannot be reasonably found by someone looking for it is not.

  3.6 While it is allowed for the crew to know the details around the various antagonist functions, it is forbidden to act on that information without valid motive (for example, evidence strongly suggesting a member of the crew is an antagonist, or reliable witnesses of a serious crime). Everyone is always expected to presume innocence until proven guilty.
  - For example, you shouldn't check PDAs, implants, and headsets, unless there is enough evidence or motive to assume the person is a traitor.

  3.7 Do not exploit game mechanics, bugs, tricks or unintended features to circumvent roleplay, to make things much easier for oneself and more unfair for others, or in any malicious capacity.
  - For example, utilizing cryo, ghost, and death mechanics to antag roll, hiding in cryo to escape from Security, or ghosting solely to fish for antagonist roles.

  3.8 Do not intentionally breach nor metagame roleplay in order to gain unfair advantages.
  - Such as, engaging someone in combat when they are busy typing something out directed at another person.
  - Fake typing to bait somebody to get closer.
  - Using roleplay as an excuse to circumvent rules
</Document>
