<Document>
  # Section 3: Powergaming

  ## Background
  Powergaming is a complex rule. Its reasons for its existence are hard for people to understand initially, as it goes against the logic of a video game and the natural urges of a player playing a video game.

  Generally speaking, the rule against powergaming is a [bold]band-aid rule[/bold].
  This means that the rule is trying to stop unwanted behavior that has little to no mechanical discouragement or prevention.

  Powergaming is a balance issue.
  If there is a problem with people hoarding equipment to the point where it is unfun for the other side, then that equipment should be tuned to make it more discouraging to hoard or prepare.

  ## Definition
  [bold]3.1[/bold] Do not powergame. Powergaming is generally defined as intentionally minmaxxing your equipment, gear, or stats to attempt to achieve the best possible loadout for a future threat that has not occurred yet, to the point where you are playing to win, instead of roleplaying.

  The definition of powergaming is highly flexible and boils down to the actions you take and the circumstances regarding your actions.
  Generally, if you have a valid in-character reason for the equipment you have, you can have that equipment.
  These reasons should be [bold]based on the events you have currently experienced in-round, and not on your character's lore or background[/bold].

  For example, it is valid to wear riot armor and carry a riot shield to the bar in the context of revolutionaries, traitor activity, or a large spike in creatures aboard the station.
  It is not valid when nothing but meteors have been pelting the station—you are effectively playing to win instead of roleplaying.

  This rule is effectively enforced as a component to rule [bold]4.4[/bold] (playing to win). If you are locking up all antagonists, shooting to kill in hostage situations, or pushing hard for executions for people who are attempting to roleplay, you are shutting down roleplay opportunities and playing to win.

  3.2  Do not rush for, hoard, or prepare equipment unrelated to your job or that you do not need. If you, in your given role, require items that do not fall within your job’s usual parameters or that you do not necessarily need, seek in-character roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them.
  - Permits stamped by the head of your department, the Head of Personnel, or the Captain are roleplay-friendly methods.

  3.3 As a non-antagonist, manufacturing dangerous, powerful, or/and out-of-the-norm items such as weapons, bombs, deadly poisons, specialized machinery, or obstructive structures without reasonable emergency or need is liable to be considered powergaming behavior. Seek in-character, roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them outside of emergency or strict need.

  3.4 As a non-antagonist, don't intentionally hide antagonist objectives in unreasonable locations.
  - For example, handing a possible antagonist objective to another member of your department is fine, while handing it to a member of a different department is not.
  - It is reasonable to assume that an item such as the handheld crew monitor or hypospray may be in the possession of another member of the medical staff, but not an engineer.
  - Hiding a possible antagonist objective somewhere in your room is okay, hiding it in a room where it cannot be reasonably found by someone looking for it is not.

  3.5 While it is allowed for the crew to know the details around the various antagonist functions, it is forbidden to act on that information without a valid motive (for example, evidence strongly suggesting a member of the crew is an antagonist, or reliable witnesses of a serious crime). Everyone is always expected to presume innocence until proven guilty.
  - For example, you shouldn't check someone's PDA unless there is enough evidence or motive to assume the person is a traitor.

  3.6 Do not exploit game mechanics, bugs, tricks, or unintended features to circumvent roleplay, to make things much easier for oneself and more unfair for others, or in any malicious capacity.
  - For example, utilizing cryo, ghost, and death mechanics to antag roll, hiding in cryo to escape from Security, or ghosting solely to fish for antagonist roles.

  3.7 Do not intentionally breach nor metagame roleplay in order to gain unfair advantages.
  - Such as, engaging someone in combat when they are busy typing something out directed at another person.
  - Fake typing to bait somebody to get closer.
  - Using roleplay as an excuse to circumvent rules
</Document>
