<Document>
  # Section 2: Metagaming

  [bold]2.1[/bold] Do not metagame (i.e. using or sharing information that your character has no way of knowing or obtaining, such as knowledge on the exact loadouts of antagonists, or things seen or heard while dead).
  - At any point in the game if someone were to ask you why your character is doing what they're doing, you should be able to provide a reasonable in-character explanation.

  [bold]2.2[/bold] Do not metacommunicate (Often calling "metacomming"). Metacomming is defined as using third-party, outside of game methods to communicate with other players who are connected in-round.
  - This includes any means of communication including text, voice, images, and video.
  - This includes being in a voice chat with other players, even if you are deafened.
  - It is your responsibility to make sure nobody else is connected to the round when you join a voice call.

  [bold]This rule is not active ONLY when:[/bold]
    - An admin specifically states the rule is not active for the current round.
    - The round is concluded and the evac shuttle has arrived at Centcomm.
    - The round is in lobby and has not started yet.

  [bold]2.3[/bold] Do not metagrudge nor metafriend. That is, treating a character unfairly solely based on the out-of-character relationship with the player.
  - Refusing someone service at a department solely based on their OOC relationship with that person would violate this rule.

  [bold]2.4[/bold] Players are allowed to retain and share knowledge of past experiences and prior shifts. However, Treating a character unfairly solely based on events outside the current round, is forbidden.
  - Treating someone with more or less suspicion or trust solely based on how often they are an antagonist would be prohibited.
  - Giving someone extra access because they helped you in a previous round would be prohibited.

  [bold]2.5[/bold] Players are allowed to form in-character relationships (friends, foes, or otherwise). However, providing unfair advantages or disadvantages solely based on those IC relationships, is forbidden.
  - ignoring serious crimes, demoting, barring from services, giving out abnormally high access, handing out normally highly restricted items, etc. based in IC relationships are all forbidden.
  - attacking another player on sight because of in-character interactions in previous rounds would violate this rule.
</Document>
