<Document>
  # Section 4: Roleplay and Characters

  4.1 If, when and where possible, always try to do things in a roleplay-friendly way and keep the roleplay rolling.

  4.2 Silicons must follow the Silicon Rules. You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon. For players who are silicons, the Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules.

  4.3 Use realistic character names, and do not use the names of real people. Names should not include titles or honorifics; and should generally be believable as the name a real person in this universe would have. Performers (clowns, mimes, musicians, boxers, etc.) have significant leeway on this, and may select gimmicky or otherwise unbelievable names as long as it is a reasonable stage name.

  4.4 You are expected to roleplay, and maintain a good level and quality of roleplay. As such, focusing solely on "winning" (such as greentexting) is strongly discouraged. So is questionable behavior unfit for an organized, civilized system and society.

  4.5 Your character is a separate entity from you, the player. Your character's actions, feelings, and knowledge in-game should be based solely on the character's experiences rather than your own as the player. Also, do keep in mind that while your character may be the main character of your story, they are not the protagonist at the center of everything.

  4.6 Do not self-antag or make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption for the crew while not being an antagonist. Examples may include: random murder, destruction or disruption, stealing of high caliber items (such as Security weapons or Command items), or intentional sabotage.

  4.7 Do not play excessively hostile or provocative characters. Playing a character accurately should never result in rule breaches. Being a major nuisance or a source of major frustration to the crew, or behaving in a way that is affecting very negatively the relaxing environment we strive to uphold, is not accepted.

  4.8 Follow proper escalation. **Antags are not required to follow this rule**. When in any sort of fight or conflict, assess the threat posed by someone before you choose how to respond to them. If someone isn't using lethal weapons, using lethal force on them is usually overescalation. Similarly, wordlessly beating someone up or batoning them is overescalation unless it's done for good reason. Security roles in particular are asked to mind this rule.

  4.9 Players are allowed and even encouraged to engage in creative gimmicks, mischief, hijinks and ideas, so long it doesn't cross the border into unacceptable behavior (self-antag, powergaming, metagaming, etc.) and so long properly and well roleplayed.
</Document>
