<Document>
  # 2.2 Metacomming
  Do not use any external methods to communicate with other players in the same game server, or who were connected to the same server during the current round.
  This is referred to as "metacomming" and includes any means of communication including text, voice, images, and video.
  This includes applications such as Discord, Steam, and other platforms, along with in-person communication.

  [color=red][bold]This is a zero-tolerance rule.[/bold][/color]
  Even if information is not being shared or abused, it may still be considered a violation of this rule.

  Due to the difficulty of determining if information is being shared, it will almost always be presumed that people who message another player they are in a round with, or who are in a voice call with another player during a round are sharing round information.

  Due to the difficulty of determining if users are abusing information that they are sharing, it will almost always be presumed that the information is being abused.

  When participating in any active voice call or channel, it is [color=red][bold]your responsibility[/bold][/color] to ensure that all players there are not playing on the server at the same time as you are.

  It is best to use LOOC or OOC to share any out-of-character information with anyone else in the round, though note it is encouraged to talk as much as possible in-character about your topic before using LOOC or OOC.

  ## Exceptions
  There are a few exceptions to this rule:
  - [color=#a4885c]All[/color] players (not just the ones you are talking to) are in the server lobby.
    - We encourage you to not communicate during this time, in order to include everyone in pre or post round discussion.
  - The server admins are hosting an event (ex. teaching events) and they have explicitly permitted metacomming.
  - The server admins are hosting certain gamemodes like Gun Game or Deathmatch and they have explicitly permitted metacomming.

  ## Streaming
  Streaming gameplay publically or privately is allowed, however:
  - You should ensure that players are not actively watching your stream while connencted to the server themselves.
  - Players shouldn't be sharing any in-round information with you that wasn't obtained from the stream directly.

  ## Teaching New Players
  Teaching new players is not exempt from this rule.
  You should be conversing with new players through entirely in-game means, if you are playing with them.
  It is highly recommended (and easier) to have the new player stream gameplay footage to you, while you yourself are not playing, and teach that way instead.
  Being physically present behind them (while also not playing yourself) is also allowed and encouraged.

  ## Examples
  The following are a few examples in order to clear up potential grey areas.

  ### Disallowed
  - Sitting in a discord voice channel/call with other people who are connected to the server when a round is taking place, even if you or the other members of the call are muted or deafened. This is still disallowed even if any or all members are ghosts or observing.
  - Sharing in-round information to Discord text channels or other external means, when the round is still ongoing.
  - Conversing with other players through means that are not in-game methods during gamemodes like Gun Game or Deathmatch when an admin has not explicitly allowed metacomming.
</Document>
