<Document>
  # The Metashield
  The metashield is a list of things that your character does not know at the start of a round. If something is shielded, your character would not act upon it. If it's not shielded, then it's something they could potentially know.

  The following are shielded:
  - Current game mode and possible antags during the current game mode.
  - All information related to the player of a character rather than the character itself.
  - All information gained while dead or a ghost.
  - The fact that a round will end.

  This does not prevent knowing that a shift will end, but it does prevent behaving in a suicidal or reckless manner towards the end of the round if there's no IC reason for it.
  These things are shielded because you are roleplaying your character and their interests, rather than yourself.

  ## Nuclear Operatives

  The existence of Nuclear Operatives beyond a myth that no one would act on is shielded.

  The supposed "Myth" is that Gorlex sends paramilitary deathsquads to NT stations on behalf of the Syndicate with the objective detonating a nuclear bomb. The idea of this happening as a myth is not shielded.

  If your character comes upon reasonable evidence that this is occuring, their existence becomes unshielded.

  The fact that the nuke disk must be protected and could be used by a bad actor to try to destroy the station is not shielded.

  The Gorlex Marauders existence and their membership in the syndicate is not shielded.

  ## Traitors

  The existence of undercover agents sent by the Syndicate to infiltrate Nanotrasen is not shielded.

  The idea of them being on the station without evidence is shielded.

  Their potential objectives are shielded.

  The fact that the syndicate may desire high-value items from the station is not shielded.

  ## Thieves

  The potential that there are people aboard the station who are capable of pickpocketing is not shielded.

  However, you should not suspect someone of being capable of pickpocketing without good reason.

  ## Chameleon and stealth Items

  Chameleon and Stealth items are shielded.

  If you have no in-character reason to suspect an item is something other than what it appears to be visually, then you cannot treat it with suspicion.

  You can suspect that an item is fake or has functionality outside its appearance, but only if you have a valid in-character reason for it.

  ## Pirates

  The fact that there are pirates in space who attack stations and shuttles for money is not shielded.

  Their bounties and how much said bounties pay is shielded.

  The innate value of items and the fact that they may be targeted by the pirates because of it is not shielded.
</Document>
