<Document>
  # Section 3: Powergaming

  [bold]The rule of thumb for most powergaming rules is you should have a valid in-character justification for your actions.[/bold]
  - To add, the In-Character justification should be reasonable. For example, having a character who is a gun-nut doesn't justify them carrying around a rifle every round.

  [bold]3.1[/bold] Do not powergame. Powergaming is defined as prioritizing “winning” over roleplay and reasonable character behavior.
  - This rule is applied especially in the case of security and antag interactions.
  - For example, if people are trying to RP a hostile scenario you shouldn't barge in guns blazing just so your side can "win" the encounter.

  [bold]3.2[/bold] While it is allowed for the crew to know vague details about antagonist functions, it is forbidden to act on that information without valid motive.
  - You shouldn't act on suspicion of certain antags being present without evidence and IC reasoning.

  [bold]3.3[/bold] Do not rush for, hoard, or prepare weapons, equipment, or other items that you do not have an in-character, roleplay-friendly explanation for having.
  - This rule is especially applied to members of command and security

  [bold]3.4[/bold] As a non-antagonist, don't intentionally hide antagonist objectives in unreasonable locations.
  - It is considered reasonable to place it somewhere where someone looking for it could reasonably find it, such as your room (as a command member), or a member of your department.
  - It is unreasonable to give it to someone who has no IC reason to have it, or stash it somewhere where nobody could reasonably find it.

  [bold]3.5[/bold] Do not exploit bugs, tricks, or unintended features to circumvent roleplay, circumvent game mechanics, or in any malicious capacity.
  - For example, utilizing cryo, ghost, and death mechanics to antag roll, hiding in cryo to escape from Security, or ghosting solely to fish for antagonist roles.

  [bold]3.6[/bold] Do not intentionally breach nor metagame roleplay in order to gain unfair advantages.
  - Such as, engaging someone in combat when they are busy typing.
  - Fake typing to bait somebody to get closer.
  - Using roleplay as an excuse to circumvent rules
</Document>
