<Document>
  # Section 6: End-of-Round, Evacuation, and Safe Havens

  6.1 Safe Havens are areas where antagonist activity is expected to be minimal, and generally non-violent. These areas are as follows:
  - The arrivals planet.
  - The arrivals shuttle.
  - The areas on station where the arrivals shuttle docks.
  - The evac shuttle after it has departed the station.
  - Central Command.

  6.2 Safe Havens are expected to remain habitable for crew throughout the course of the round, and should not be targets of destruction by antagonists. Some leeway may be given for accidents, but generally antagonists should avoid causing trouble in these areas.

  6.3 Disruptive behavior in safe havens is forbidden. This includes but is not limited to: murder (both with objectives and without), the usage of explosives (both non-lethal and lethal), the usage of firearms, releasing harmful chemical bombs, and breaking into important secure areas.

  6.4 Conflicts within a safe haven must remain verbal and non-violent. An exception is made for situations where there are strong roleplay reasons to do otherwise, and for Security, who may perform arrests non-lethally.

  6.5 Antagonists are encouraged to pursue their objectives before the arrival of the evac shuttle. Waiting until evac arrives to perform your objectives is a form of powergaming and does not cultivate fun for other players.

  6.6 Antagonists should pursue their objectives outside of safe havens when possible. Performing violent actions within a safe haven is a form of powergaming and does not cultivate fun for other players during the round.

  6.7 At the end of the round, antagonists are required to no longer pursue their objectives, since there is the expectation that they are attempting to lie low while in a Nanotrasen-controlled area. Major antagonists which are not crew-aligned such as revenants, dragons, wizards, and nuclear agents, are expected to not behave violently at the end of the round, and either stay behind when evac leaves or lie low.
</Document>
