<Document>
  # Section 4: Roleplay and Characters

  [bold]4.1[/bold] If, when and where possible, always try to do things in a roleplay-friendly way.

  [bold]4.2[/bold] Silicons must follow the [textlink="Silicon Rules" link="SiliconRules"].
  - You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon.
  - For players who are silicons, the Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules.

  [bold]4.3[/bold] Use realistic character names, and do not use the names of real people.
  - Names should not include titles or honorifics; and should generally be believable as the name a real person in this universe would have.
  - Performers (clowns, mimes, musicians, boxers, etc.) have significant leeway on this, and may select gimmicky or otherwise unbelievable names within reason.

  [bold]4.4[/bold] You are expected to roleplay, and maintain a good level and quality of roleplay.
  - As such, focusing solely on "winning" or "playing to win" is prohibited.

  [bold]4.5[/bold] Your character is a separate entity from you, the player.
  - Your character's actions, feelings, and knowledge in-game should be based solely on the character's experiences rather than your own as the player.
  - Keep in mind that while your character may be the main character of your story, they are not the protagonist at the center of everything.

  [bold]4.6[/bold] Do not self-antag or make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption for the crew while not being an antagonist.

  [bold]4.7[/bold] Do not play excessively hostile, abrasive, or provocative characters.
  - Playing a character accurately should never result in rule breaches.

  [bold]4.8[/bold] As a non-antag, follow proper escalation.
  - When in any sort of fight or conflict, evaluate the threat posed by the other side.
  - If someone isn't using lethal weapons, using lethal force on them is usually over-escalation.
  - Wordlessly beating someone up or batoning them is over-escalation unless it's done for good reason.
  - Security and Command roles are especially asked to mind this rule.

  [bold]4.9[/bold] Players are allowed and even encouraged to engage in creative gimmicks, mischief, hijinks and ideas, so long as it is well roleplayed and doesn't violate any other rules.
</Document>
