<Document>
  # Gray

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AppearanceGray" Scale="2" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Gray are an exterrestrial species with origins from galaxies far away. Although it is unknown how long Grays have been known to other species outside of hoaxes and delusional hysteria, they appear to have a vast knowledge of terra's pop culture from centuries ago as well as a large knowledge of the late 20th century on the planet also.

  ## Biology
  Gray appear to have a unique biology compared to most other species, this includes Gray Respiratory Organs or the "Oogmards" to channel harmonic sounds.

  ## Dialects
  Gray dialect has adapted from many years of attempting to communicate with humanoid species to standards acceptable for NanoTrasen's employment Department to introduce them aboard stations, many unsure of their way of speaking may find them abnormal,
<Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignEVA" Scale="4" Caption=""/>

</Box>

  ## Low Pressure Living
  Due to the poor construction of saucers and other flying objects, Gray have developed better to withstand lower pressure environments than most other species.

  Gray are more physically frail than most other species, but their habitats have rendered them more resilient to thermal exposure and radiation.

  ## Gray Name Conventions
  Gray Vines have a plethora of name styles across the many galaxies but usually fall into two categories,

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterLegitSpaceCops" Scale="4" Caption="Space Cops is in Theatres!"/>

  </Box>
  ### Terra Observers

  Observers are known for their love of Terra's late 20th century culture, They usually strive to emanate their favourite cultural staples of the time.

  [color=#ffa500]Caution! To avoid causing RP issues, try to stick to concepts related to the late 20th century rather than directly referencing media or famous figures.[/color]

  ### Glorpii Zasbaahs
  Glorpiis are the blanketed term for those who didn't observe the 'Gray Golden Years' or those without an interest in the archived taped reruns on Xehennel L-5, These names are close to their Dialect, usually being irregular to most humanoid species standards.

  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Gii Wee Pleeknarp
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Sneed Actionmann
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Tomm Hinks
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Goose Compryshun
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Zee'b Nark
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Skibidi Fortnite
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Amongus Despacito
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Kill Bill
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Ohio Rizzler
</Document>
