<Document>
  # Trailblazer Station 14 Server Rules
  This is a roleplay server, meaning that roleplay is expected. Please take the time to read all the rules; if you are playing on the server, you are expected to follow the rules.

  [color=#ff0000]Not reading the rules is by no means an excuse to break them.
  The rules are different from many other SS14 servers. Read them, seriously.[/color]

  ## 0. Core Rules
  Core Rules apply at all times, even between rounds. Some of these rules are fully or partially zero tolerance - this means you will get immediately permanently banned upon breaking them.

  - [textlink="0.0. Admins have final say" link="0-0"]
  - [textlink="0.1. Players must act and be at least 16 years old" link="0-1"]
  - [textlink="0.2. No Hate Speech or Discriminatory Language" link="0-2"]
  - [textlink="0.3. No erotic/sexual/shock content" link="0-3"]
  - [textlink="0.4. Don't be a dick" link="0-4"]
  - [textlink="0.5. Do not use multiple accounts (especially for ban evading), and do not share them" link="0-5"]
  - [textlink="0.6. Use only English" link="0-6"]
  - [textlink="0.7. Do not use bugs, exploits, cheats or macros" link="0-7"]
  - [textlink="0.8. Do not communicate with other players in the round outside of that round" link="0-8"]
  - [textlink="0.9. Do not abuse, ignore, or threaten with AHelp" link="0-9"]
  - [textlink="0.10. Do not use OOC chats to share current round information" link="0-10"]

  ## 1. Roleplay Rules
  These rules apply outside the lobby (in the round). These rules do not apply to ghosts, spectators, dead chat and (L)OOC chats.

  - [textlink="1.0. Roleplay a regular person" link="1-0"]
  - [textlink="1.1. Use realistic character names, and don't use names of famous people" link="1-1"]
  - [textlink="1.2. Do not metagame, follow the Metashield" link="1-2"]
  - [textlink="1.3. Don't interfere with cryosleep/newly arrived or respawned players" link="1-3"]
  - [textlink="1.4. Self-antagging is FAKE! Follow escalation rules" link="1-4"]
  - [textlink="1.5. Do not cause excessive death, damage, or destruction" link="1-5"]
  - [textlink="1.6. Do not stall the round" link="1-6"]
  - [textlink="1.7. Follow the rules of your antag role" link="1-7"]

</Document>
